const questions = [

  {
    question: "How long does it take the Earth to travel once around the Sun?",
    options: ["A year", "A day", "12 hours"],
    answer: "A year",
    category: "Explore Our Special Planet 🌍",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Venus and Earth have similar size and composition. Yet Venus is much, much hotter. Why?",
    options: [
      "Venus's magnetic field is very strong",
      "Venus's rotation is very fast",
      "Venus's atmosphere is very thick",
    ],
    answer: "Venus's atmosphere is very thick",
    category: "Explore Our Special Planet 🌍",
  },
  {
    question: "What protects us from most space rocks?",
    options: ["Atmosphere", "Moon", "Magnetosphere"],
    answer: "Atmosphere",
    category: "Explore Our Special Planet 🌍",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The Earth is the only rocky planet in the Solar System where you can use a traditional compass. Why?",
    options: [
      "There is no North Pole on other planets",
      "Earth has a magnetic field",
      "Compasses are forbidden beyond Earth",
    ],
    answer: "Earth has a magnetic field",
    category: "Explore Our Special Planet 🌍",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which celestial body could potentially host life, like the Earth?",
    options: ["Jupiter", "Mercury", "Saturn's moon Enceladus"],
    answer: "Saturn's moon Enceladus",
    category: "Explore Our Special Planet 🌍",
  },

  {
    question: "What is the Sun mostly made of?",
    options: ["Hydrogen", "Helium", "Oxygen"],
    answer: "Hydrogen",
    category: "Discover the Sun's Secrets ☀️",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the Sun's surface temperature?",
    options: [
      "5,500 degrees Celsius",
      "10,000 degrees Celsius",
      "15,000 degrees Celsius",
    ],
    answer: "5,500 degrees Celsius",
    category: "Discover the Sun's Secrets ☀️",
  },
  {
    question:"What is the second most abundant element in the Sun after hydrogen?",
    options: ["Helium", "Oxygen", "Carbon"],
    answer: "Helium",
    category: "Discover the Sun's Secrets ☀️",
  },
  {
    question: "How much of the Solar System's mass does the Sun comprise?",
    options: ["About 75%", "About 50%", "About 99%"],
    answer: "About 99%",
    category: "Discover the Sun's Secrets ☀️",
  },
  {
    question:"What is the distance between the Sun and Earth called in astronomy?",
    options: ["Solar mile", "Astronomical unit", "Light year"],
    answer: "Astronomical unit",
    category: "Discover the Sun's Secrets ☀️",
  },

{
    question:"All the Solar System planets have moons.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False",
    category: "Astronomy Facts: True or False? 🌌",
}, 
{
    question:"There are more stars in the Universe than grains of sand on all of the Earth’s beaches.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True",
    category: "Astronomy Facts: True or False? 🌌",
},
{
    question:"Planets, stars, and galaxies comprise only 5% of all the matter in the Universe.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "True",
    category: "Astronomy Facts: True or False? 🌌",
},
{
    question:"The phases of the Moon are caused by the Earth's shadow.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False",
    category: "Astronomy Facts: True or False? 🌌",
},
{
    question:"Mercury, the closest planet to the Sun, is also the hottest planet in the Solar System.",
    options: ["True", "False"],
    answer: "False",
    category: "Astronomy Facts: True or False? 🌌",
},
{
    question:"What is the hottest planet in the Solar System?",
    options: ["Mercury", "Venus", "Mars"],
    answer: "Venus",
    category: "Solar System Objects 🪐",
},
{
    question:"What is the largest moon in the Solar System?",
    options: ["Titan", "Ganymede", "Callisto"],
    answer: "Ganymede",
    category: "Solar System Objects 🪐",
},
{
    question:"What is the fastest-spinning large body in the Solar System?",
    options:["Apophis","Europa","Haumea"],
    answer:"Haumea",
    category:"Solar System Objects 🪐"
},
{
    question:"Which planet has the sharpest temperature changes?",
    options:["Mercury","Venus","Uranus"],
    answer:"Mercury",
    category:"Solar System Objects 🪐"
},
{
    question:"Some Solar System planets have never been approached by spacecraft.",
    options:["True","False"],
    answer:"False",
    category:"Space Exploration 🚀"
},
{
    question:"The International Space Station is the most expensive object ever built.",
    options:["True","False"],
    answer:"True",
    category:"Space Exploration 🚀"
},  
{
    question:"Astronauts on the ISS become weightless because there's no gravity in space.",
    options:["True","False"],
    answer:"False",
    category:"Space Exploration 🚀"  
},
{
    question:"Astronauts grow taller in space.",
    options:["True","False"],
    answer:"True",
    category:"Space Exploration 🚀"
},
{
    question:"Apollo astronauts' footprints on the Moon have been already erased by the wind.",
    options:["True","False"],
    answer:"False",
    category:"Space Exploration 🚀"
},
{
    question:"There's a sudden streak of light across the sky. What did you likely witness?",
    options:["Meteor","Comet","Asteroid"],
    answer:"Meteor",
    category:"How Good Are You at Stargazing?🌠"
},
{
    question:"You observe a pale band of light stretching across the night sky from horizon to horizon. What is it?",
    options:["Milky Way","Andromeda Galaxy","Orion Nebula"],
    answer:"Milky Way",
    category:"How Good Are You at Stargazing?🌠"
},
{
    question:"You notice a rhythmically blinking object moving across the sky. What could this be?",
    options:["Satellite","Airplane","Comet"],
    answer:"Airplane",
    category:"How Good Are You at Stargazing?🌠"
},
{
    question:"You're trying to observe a faint object in the night sky. What technique can you use to see it better?",
    options:["Look slightly away from the object","Stare directly at the object","Close one eye"],
    answer:"Look slightly away from the object",
    category:"How Good Are You at Stargazing?🌠"
},
{
    question:"You see a bright yellowish dot that doesn’t twinkle. What object is it?",
    options:["Jupiter","Venus","Mars"],
    answer:"Jupiter",
    category:"How Good Are You at Stargazing?🌠"
}

];

export default questions;
